So far, we've seen two distinct ways to process
到目前为止 我们已经了解了
data with Python, operators and functions.
在 Python 中处理数据的两种方式 即运算符和函数
We've used operators like these,
我们使用了这样的运算符
which process the two values on either side of the operator.
它们会对运算符两侧的两个值进行处理
We've also used functions like print and len.
还使用了 print 和 len 等函数
Functions are very similar to operators.
函数和运算符非常相似
In fact, the only real difference is in how they look.
实际上 唯一区别是它们的外观
Function Inputs are put in parentheses rather than being placed next to an operator,
函数输入放入括号里 而不是放在运算符旁边
and functions have descriptive names rather than short symbols.
函数具有描述性名称 而不是简短的符号
There is a third technique for operating on values, methods.
还有处理值的第三种技巧 即方法
The best way to learn about methods is with an example.
学习方法的最佳方式是看一个示例
Consider this title method.
看看这个 title() 方法
Methods are related to functions,
方法和函数相关
but unlike functions, methods are associated with specific types of objects.
但是和函数不同的是 方法与特定类型的对象有关
That is, there are different methods depending on the type of data you're working with.
也就是说 不同的方法取决于要处理的数据类型
In this example, the object is a string with the value
在此示例中 对象是一个字符串
Sebastian Thrun and we are calling its title method.
值是 Sebastian Thrun 我们要调用其 title() 方法
The method returns a string in title case,
该方法返回一个职称形式的字符串
meaning the first letter of each word is capitalized.
也就是每个单词的首字母都大写
So methods are functions that belong to an object,
因此 方法是属于某个对象的函数
an object, for example, being a string.
例如字符串对象
Let's try another string method, islower().
我们再看另一个字符串方法 islower()
The lower method checks one of the characters in a string or lowercase.
islower() 方法会检查字符串中的字符是否为小写形式
In this case, the string object is sebastian thrun.
在此示例中 字符串对象是 sebastian thrun
Is lower returns true since there are
islower() 返回 true
no uppercase letters you've probably
因为没有大写字母
noticed that when we call the is lower and title methods,
你可能注意到了 当我们调用方法 islower() 和 title() 时
we use parentheses, but we haven't put
我们使用括号 但是并没有像调用函数那样
anything in them like we did when calling functions.
在括号里放入任何内容
Those inputs in the parentheses are called arguments.
括号里的输入称为参数
Since methods or special types of functions that belong to an object,
因为方法是属于对象的特殊函数
the object is always the first argument to a method.
对象始终是方法的第一个参数
So, is lower and title actually did have
因此 虽然括号里什么也没有
an argument although there was nothing in the parentheses.
但是 islower() 和 title() 的确具有参数
The argument is disguised as the string object.
参数伪装成了字符串对象
Let's try a method that takes more arguments than just the object, count.
我们来尝试一个包含多个参数（而不仅仅只是对象本身）的方法 叫做 count()
Here, the count method returns how many times the substring fish occurs in the string.
这里 count() 方法返回字符串中出现子字符串“fish”的次数
The object is the string, one fish,
对象是字符串
two fish, red fish, blue fish,
“one fish, two fish, red fish, blue fish”
and the method is dot count,
方法是 .count
and four occurrences of the word fish exist in the string.
单词 fish 在该字符串中出现了四次